Curtis Dwight LaGrone

1306 Wildwood Trail Anna, Texas, 75409 dwightlagrone@yahoo.com

Profile:

I am a seasoned GIS Professional with more that 22 years experience in Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and Global Positioning Systems (GPS). Strong background and hands on in ESRI Enterprise GIS system design, implementation, and administration. Strong background in ArcGIS Server, Geodatabase, SQL Server, ArcGIS Online. Some experience with Google Maps Engine and Amazon Cloud Services

S:			Projects:	
ESRI (ArcGIS)	 Power Point 	 Jade/EJS 	Storm Water Fees	
ArcSDE	 Adobe 	 JQuery 	 Handicap Ramps 	
 ArcGIS Online 	Flex	REST	 OSSI/CAD 	
 SQL Server 	 Silverlight 	JSON	 VUEWorks 	
 Mongo DB 	 Heroku 	 Node js 	 Canopy Study 	
AutoCAD	 Github 	 Express js 	 Zoning Web Map 	
Word	 JavaScript 	 Agile 	 200' Notices 	
Excel	 HTML/CSS 			

Experience:

City of Sherman 2015-Present

GIS Manager

• Manage the development of the City's Geographic Information System (GIS).

- Assists in the development requirements, tasks, and resource assignments, ensuring that
 approved quality levels and deadlines are met.
- Prepares GIS project plans and schedules to include coordinating resources, tasks, and work assignments.
- Develops standards for GIS deployment and use within the City. Serves as a liaison with GIS vendors for the and maintenance of GIS-related resource.
- Setup and manage Geodatabase. Setup new users in SQL Server.
- Applications supported by GIS included: VUEWorks, OSSI.CAD and RouteSmart (in progress).
- Other duties: create maps, perform spatial analysis and manage the City of Sherman's GIS online account.
- Created and manage approximately 20 GIS websites for the City of Sherman. (CSS, Javascript, HTML, Rest, IIS, JSON)

North Texas Toll way Authority

GIS Developer 2015

- Perform design, development and maintenance of geospatial databases and assist with technical oversight of GIS applications.
 - Manage SQL Sever
 - Create new users and with permissions
 - Create and manage new tables
 - Setup triggers
 - Creates and manage 3 GIS websites
 - Propose and lead innovative GIS approaches to solving complex business problems, utilizing available research and data. Responsible for companywide design and maintenance of GIS web applications.
 - Create and print various company maps and map books.
 - Work with surrounding entities for sharing of GIS data.
 - Work with leaders across the organization to define, develop and review process around mapping, reporting, data needs, and analyses, then deliver on a regular basis to appropriate parties.

City of McKinney 2012-2015

GIS Supervisor

- Manage the development of the City's Geographic Information System (GIS). Supervise professional, technical and clerical personnel.
 - Supervise a team of staff including programmers,, data managers, analyst and support specialist.
 - Identifies and implements appropriate uses of GIS and GPS throughout the City.
 - Manage budget and project cost.
 - Recruit and train staff
 - Manage the development of GIS software packages.
 - Purchase new equipment
 - Keep up to data with new technology
 - Make sure projects keep to pre-determined deadlines
 - Negotiated contracts

2012-2015

Experience (cont.):

GIS Programmer 2009-2012

- Job responsibilities included maintaining ArcSDE databases and managing city web applications.
 - Install and Setup SQL Server (SQL server is the database used for our GIS database)
 - Create and setup new users (There was approximately 100 users that accessed our GIS data)
 - ArcGIS Server/ArcSDE :Installation, configuration, and Geodatabase administration: Backups, security, post, reconcile and compress.
 - GIS Applications development, customization and Integration with other software packages (OSS-Police, Firehouse-Fire, Numix-Public Works and Engov-Development Services) project manager.
 - GPS: applications development, build data dictionaries, data post processing, train city employees such as traffic, street, fire fighters, water and sewer to carry out data collection.
 - Created and managed approximately 20 GIS websites. Technologies used: JavaScript, Flex, Silverlight, CSS, HTML, Dojo, REST, ESRI API, Internet Information Services (IIS) Manager.
 - Created custom applications using Python (200' notices with property owners list)

GIS Analyst/Technician 1994-2009

- Job responsibilities included supporting Public Safety and Engineering.
 - Spatial Analysis projects for Engineering, Planning, Water, Sewer, Police and Fire Support.
 - Response Mapping, Inventory Management, Fire Hydrant Data, Water, Sewer and Storm Pipes.
 - Council and Voting Precincts, Parcels, Annexations and Boundary Agreements. ArcGIS Vector,
 - · Point and Polygon Editing,
 - Arc View geocoding, Map Production. 9-1-1 Addressing, Map Book Production.

Education:

Free Code Camp - online 2017

Free Code Camp's Front End Development Program

This online course consisted of basic and intermediate algorithm scripting challenges using Javascript. Also the basic, intermediate, and advanced front end development projects.

Frame System by Accuragraph and the Personnel Computer using AutoCAD software. Earned 45 quarter In the projects technologies used: Javascript, HTML, Jade, EJS, CSS, GIT, Heroku, JSON, REST

National Education Center 1989-1991

Glendale Arizona

 Occupational Associate Degree in Drafting Technology and AutoCAD. - Twelve months Electro-Mechanical Drafting and Six months Computer Aided Drafting with the use of Hewlett Packard 1000-ADC400 Main Frame System by Accuragraph and the Personnel Computer using AutoCAD software. Earned 45 quarter credit hours applying CAD.

McKinney High School 1986-1989

McKinney Texas